Guide to the Cornell University Centennial Celebration Records, 1957-1967, 1960-1965 (bulk)
Cornell University Centennial Celebration Records, 1957-1967, 1960-1965 (bulk)
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University, Centennial Celebration Records1957-1967, 1960-1965 (bulk)
47-4-798
Cornell University. Centennial Celebration.
12.9
Correspondence, newsclippings, photographs and subject files
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
This collection contains materials relating to Cornell University's Centennial Celebration which took place in 1965. Planning material, correspondence, speeches and photographs all detail the events which took place in celebration of Cornell University's 100th year.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records concerning the year-long Cornell University Centennial observance (1964-65) and the related development program, including correspondence and preliminary plans and statements; mimeographed minutes, memoranda, studies, reports And agenda of the Planning Committee, established in 1960; statements of long-range plans and goals submitted to the Committee by the Deans of each of the colleges and schools in Ithaca; reports prepared by the various university departments and divisions for meetings with the Sub-Committees on the Humanities, the Natural Sciences, and the Social Sciences and reports of these sub-committees; papers written by staff and faculty members on university-wide problems; drafts and final copies of Centennial brochures; correspondence, scripts, and memoranda mainly of the Centennial Celebration Committee pertaining to Convocation (October 1964), Cornell Week at Lincoln Center (March 1965), Charter Week (April-May, 1965), the presentation at Cornell of Berlioz's Te Deum by the Philadelphia Orchestra, Alumni Reunion Week culminating in the son et lumière program, written and produced by Donald Mainwaring and other Centennial events; also programs, texts of addresses and symposia and other printed matter, committee minutes, schedules, invitations, photographs, press releases, and tape recordings; congratulatory letters and approximately 120 scrolls and similar documents from colleges, universities and learned societies here and abroad. The chief correspondents are Robert Kidera and John Marcham; other persons represented in the records include Sir Eric Ashby, Morris Bishop, Walter Brusk, Richard H. Comstock, Alfred R. Crawford, Arthur H. Dean, Mary H. Donlon, George Healy, Karel Husa, Ernest Leet, Thomas Mackesey, Deane W. Malott, Otakar Matousek, Janson Noyes, Jrl, Eugene Ormandy, James A. Perkins, Felix Reichmann, Adlai Stevenson and James L. Zwingle.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University. Centennial Celebration; Ashby, Eric, 1904-; Bishop, Morris, 1893-1973; Bruska, Walter; Comstock, Richard H.; Crawford, Alfred R.; Dean, Arthur H.; Donlon, Mary H., 1893-1977; Healy, George; Husa, Karel, 1921-; Kiderea, Robert; Leet, Ernest D.; Mackesey, Thoms William, 1908-1976; Mainwaring, Donald; Malott, Deane Waldo, 1898-; Marcham, John; Matou-sek, Otakar; Noyes, Janson Jr.; Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-; Perkins, James Alfred, 1911-; Reichmann, Felix; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1936-; Zwingle, James L
Subjects:
Cornell University--Addresses, essays, lectures; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae; Cornell University--Anniversaries, etc.; Cornell University--Pictorial works; Cornell University--History; Cornell University--Planning; Lighting--Special effects; Son et lumière
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Record of Delegates, Scrolls and Greetings Received During the Centennial Year
Boxes 1-2
Series II. Complete Set of Speeches at All Major Events of the Centennial Year
Box 3
Series III. Centennial Correspondence, Publications and Planning Material
Boxes 4-8
Series IV. Cornell Centennial Planning Committee
Boxes 9-10
Series V. President's Office
Boxes 11-13
Series VI. Tapes
Series VII. Collection #47-4-1474
Boxes 1-3
Series VIII. Memorabilia
Box 14
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Record of Delegates, Scrolls and Greetings Received During the Centennial Year
  - University of Agraria (Peru)-parchment scroll, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Bologna-scroll, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Free University of Brussels (Belgium)-parchment scroll, October 19, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Chalmers University of Technology-silver plate, October 2, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Ohio State University-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Utah-scroll, September 7, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Los Andes-silver plate, October 5, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Puerto Rico-scroll, 1964 (Box 1)
  - New York University-scroll, September 13, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Ibadan-scroll, September 22, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Washington-scroll, October 1, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Harvard University-scroll, October 1, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Zurich-scroll, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Cambridge-scroll, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Catholic University of Louvain-scroll, July 20, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Michigan State University-illuminated scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Glasgow, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Leyden-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Heidelberg-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Singapore-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Xi Society-scroll, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Royal College of Music-illuminated scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Oxford-scroll, September, 1964 (Box 1)
  - University of Manchester (England)-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Princeton University-scroll, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Vanderbilt University-2 scrolls, October 9, 1964 (Box 1)
  - C.U. Centennial-hostess ribbon, October 9, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Index cards of the delegates and scrolls and greetings received (Box 1)
  - The Cornell Daily Sun, Centennial Edition, April 27, 1965 (Box 2)
  - The Cornell Daily Sun, Centennial Edition, unfolded copy, April 27, 1965 (Box 41)
  - Brown University-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Indiana University-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Vassar College-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Yale University-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Washington State University-message of congratulations, October 9, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Wayne State University-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - University of Texas, scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - University of the Philippines-scroll, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Union College, scroll, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences-greetings, April 20, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Agraria University (Peru)-scroll, October 1, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bryant College, scroll, February 3, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - American University-letter, February 16, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Calcutta University-letter, September 22, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - London School of Economics and Finance-letter, September 30, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - University of Bombay-letter, August 11, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Alabama A and M College-letter, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Montana State University-congratulatory letter, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - University of Liberia-scroll, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - University of Kentucky-scroll, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hebrew University of Jerusalem-congratulatory message, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - National Academy of Sciences-scroll, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - University of Iowa-scroll, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Iowa State University-greetings, September 11, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Oslo University-letter, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - University of Los Andes-letter, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Kyoto University-letter, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - American University of Beirut-greetings, October 9, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - University of Chicago-letter, October 9, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - University of Michigan-scroll, October 6, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - University of Tokyo-scroll, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - University of Rhode Island-scroll, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Columbia University-scroll, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Dartmouth College-scroll, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Arizona State University-scroll, August 11, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - University of Edinburgh-scroll, October, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - U.S. Military Academy-scroll, October 9, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - University of Paris-scroll, October 1, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - University of Sydney-scroll, July 20, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Letter from Joseph M. Roland-directory of European programs, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Cornell University Centennial "Academic Procession and Convocation", October 9, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Record of letters of appreciation, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Personal telegrams to President James Perkins, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Series II. Complete Set of Speeches at All Major Events of the Centennial Year
  - Jose Limon at Lincoln Center, March 9, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Burnham Kelly at Lincoln Center, March 9, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Morris G. Bishop at C.U. Charter Day Convocation Address, April 27, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Charter Week Symposia: A Program for the Natural Sciences (panel discussion and individual speeches)
    - P.B. Medawar, April 28, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Philip Morrison, April 28, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - George B. Kistiakowsky, April 28, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Mark Kac, April 28, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - P.B. Medawar, April 28, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Charter Week Symposia: A Program for the Social Sciences
    - Paul Samuelson, April 29, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - John Roche, April 29, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - H. Stuart Hughes, April 29, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Raymond Aron, April 29, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Charter Week Symposia: A Program for the Humanities
    - John Halloway, April 30, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Herbert J. Muller, April 30, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Henry-Russell Hitchcock, April 30, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Ferruccio Rossi-Landi, April 30, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Charter Week Symposia: Concluding Symposium-"The Great Problems"
    - John Halloway, May 1, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Raymond Aron, May 1, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Peter B. Medawar, May 1, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - "Cornell in Sound and Light" (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Series III. Centennial correspondence, publications and planning material
  - Cornell University Centennial materials, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Centennial newspaper articles, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Centennial Celebration-news releases, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Centennial-Biographical sketches and lecturers, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Centennial Campaign-Trustees preliminary statement (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Centennial-brochures and pamphlets (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Centennial photographs (Box 4)
  - Cornell Centennial-Dvorak-Requiem Project, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Centennial-correspondence and committee reports, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Centennial-awards committee, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Centennial-general information and correspondence, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Centennial-Convocation arrangements, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Centennial Celebration-Publications Committee, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Centennial-General Information, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Cornell Centennial-Lincoln Center, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Centennial-Lincoln Center, June 1964-January 1965 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Cornell Centennial-International Conference of Students, January 24-29, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Cornell Centennial-Lincoln Center, February-June, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Cornell Centennial-New York Times articles, March 10-12, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Centennial-John "Art: USA;" Cornell showing at the Whitney Museum, March, 24, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Centennial-Wordsworth Exhibit, March 5-April 17, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Centennial-Charter Week, January-May, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Cornell Centennial-Reunion Weekend, June, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Cornell Centennial-Fenton Historical Society in Jamestown, NY, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Cornell Centennial campaign; miscellaneous correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, 1961-1964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Student Centennial Committee, 1962-1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Centennial movie, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Cornell University; Cornell Athletics, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Centennial campaign; correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Proceedings dinner meeting for the C.U. Centennial campaign, January 24, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Cornell University convocation arrangements, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Centennial campaign, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The university and the arts; C.U. Centennial collection, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Cornell University convocation, October 9, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Cornell Centennial convocation, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Ithaca Journal article for the Cornell Centennial, 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Centennial movie, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Committee for the Cornell Centennial celebration, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Centennial-Lincoln Center, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Centennial-Lincoln Center, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Cornell Centennial-Lincoln Center, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Centennial-Lincoln Center exhibit, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Centennial-Student's International Conference, January-February, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Cornell University Centennial symposium and charter week, April, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Centennial events, June, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Cornell Centennial Ashby Convocation Speech, Oct.-Dec., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Cornell Centennial-Reunion Week, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Cornell Centennial-Charter Week, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Centennial; Correspondence from Dr. Matousek to President J. Perkins, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Cornell University commencement photograph (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Cornell University newsletters, pamphlets and brochures related to the Centennial
    - Miscellaneous Cornell University newsletters, pamphlets and brochures related to the centennial (Box 8)
    - Cornell Alumni News, November 1964 (Box 8)
    - "Cornell University "In excellence and diversity.. ." (Box 8)
    - A Message to Business..., November 1962 (Box 8)
    - New Directions in Chemistry, December 1964 (Box 8)
    - Center for International Studies: A Project for $73.2 Million Cornell University Centennial Campaign, November 1962 (Box 8)
    - The First Essential Endowment for Faculty Salaries: A Project in the $73.2 million Cornell University Centennial Campaign (Box 8)
    - Graduate Center: A project in the Cornell University Centennial Campaign for $73,200,000 (Box 8)
    - A Freshman Center for Cornell: A Project in the $73.2 million Cornell University Centennial Campaign (Box 8)
    - A Law Residence Center for Cornell in memory of Charles Evans Hughes: A Project in the $73.2 million Cornell University Centennial Campaign (Box 8)
    - The School of Education: A Project in the Cornell University Centennial Campaign for $73,200,000 (Box 8)
    - Athletics at Cornell Diversity and Dividends: A Project in the Cornell University Centennial Campaign for $73,200,000 (Box 8)
    - The Physical Sciences Building: A Project in the Cornell University Centennial Campaign For $73,200,000 (Box 8)
    - Willard Straight Hall: A Project in the Cornell University Centennial Campaign For $73,200,000 (Box 8)
    - The Society for the Humanities: A Project in the $73.2 million Cornell University Centennial Campaign (Box 8)
    - An Investment in Scholars and Scholarship: A Project in the Cornell University Centennial Campaign for $73,200,000 (Box 8)
    - Commemorative Gift Opportunities: Cornell University Centennial Campaign (Box 8)
    - "For Learning and for the Life of Man:" Cornell University Centennial Campaign (Box 8)
    - The Measure of Excellence: Teaching at Cornell (Box 8)
    - Announcement of the Cornell University Centennial Campaign (Box 8)
    - The Centennial Year 1961-1962.. .and beyond: Land-Grant Universities and Colleges (Box 8)
    - Charting the Second Century Under the Land-Grant Philosophy of Education (Box 8)
    - And Service to All Mankind: Cornell University Centennial 1865-1965 (Box 8)
    - The Universities and the Arts: Cornell University Centennial Celebration; Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, March 9-12, 1965 (Box 8)
    - The Universities and the Arts James A. Perkins: Cornell University Centennial Celebration, March 9, 1965 (Box 8)
    - Major Gifts for Cornell Suggestions for Volunteers: Cornell University Centennial Campaign (Box 8)
    - Cornell Centennial Addresses: International Conference of Students (Box 8)
    - Worker's Handbook: Cornell University Centennial Campaign-pamphlet, February, 1964 (Box 8)
    - "For Learning and for the Life of Man" Campaign Facts Book: Cornell University Centennial Campaign-pamphlet (Box 8)
    - Giving Securities to Cornell A Brief Compendium: Cornell University Centennial Campaign (Box 8)
    - Cornell University Centennial Symposium-Apr. 28-May 1, 1965-lecture notes (Box 8)
    - Cornell University Centennial Symposium-Apr. 28-May 1, 1965-lecture notes
    - The introductory remarks of Franklin Long, April 28, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Peter B. Medawar's lecture, April 28, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Mark Kac's lecture, April 28, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - George B. Kistiakowsy's lecture, April 28, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Philip Morrison's lecture, April, 28, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Rudolf B. Shlesinger's lecture, April 29, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - M. Raymond Aron's lectures, April 29, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Comment on Raymond Aron's "A program for the social sciences", April 29-30, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - John Roche's lecture, April 29, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Paul Samuelson's lecture, April 28, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - William R. Keat's lecture, April 30, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - John Halloway's lecture, April 30, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Henry Russell Hitchcock's lecture, April 30, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Herbert J. Muller's lecture, April 30, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Ferruccio Ross-Landi's lecture, April 30, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Max Black's lecture, May 1, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Peter B. Medawar's lecture, May 1,1965 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Cornell Centennial Planning Committee
  - University Faculty Committee on Student Affairs, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Committee on long-range planning, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Medical services at Cornell for students, faculty and employees, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Admission of the undergraduate to the university, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Faculty compensation and benefits, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Honors work at Cornell, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - The role of the student union in the University community (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Educational opportunities in the freshman year (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Academic advising in the University (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Non-curricular programs of the university (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - A long look at the Cornell University Graduate School (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - The responsibilities and functions of Cornell United Religious Work, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Report of physical education and athletics, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - International interests of Cornell University, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Projected costs, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Statement by Dean of the Agricultural School, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Statement by the Dean of the School of Architecture, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Statement by the Dean of Arts and Sciences, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Statement by the Dean of Business and Public Administration, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Statement by the Dean of Education, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Statement by the Dean of Engineering, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Statement by the Dean of the Graduate School, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Statement by the Dean of Home Economics, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Statement by the Dean of Hotel Administration, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Statement by the Dean of I.L.R., 1961 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Statement by the Dean of the Law School, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Statement by the Dean of the Graduate School of Nutrition, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Statement by the Dean of the N.Y.S. Veterinary College, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Centennial Planning Committee-planning and suggestions (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Centennial Planning Committee reports (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Centennial Development Program, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - C.P.C. Statements on B.P.A. Endowed Colleges and Policy Questions, 1957-1958 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Preliminary Statements for Colleges of Architecture and Arts and Sciences, 1958-1959 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - A Preliminary Statement on Problems of University Development, January 8, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, August 30-November 1, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, Nov.-Dec., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, January-March, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, March-April, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, May, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, May-June, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, June, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, June-July, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, July-October, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, October-December, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, December, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, January-February, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, March, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, April-June, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Cornell Centennial Committee, June-November, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Freshman Center, 1961-1963 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Society for the Humanities, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - International Center, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Suggestions for the Centennial Letterhead (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Nostalgia Piece, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Undergraduate Library (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Living at Cornell, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Major Gifts for Cornell-guide for chairmen, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Major Gifts for Cornell-Worker's Handbook (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Major Gifts Handbook-final draft (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Major Gifts Worker's Kit (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Centennial Campaign Brochure (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Centennial Campaign Brochure (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Centennial Campaign Announcement (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Cornell Photo Mural Exhibit (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - "Cornell' Plan for Excellence", November 27, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - "Cornell's Plan for Excellence", 1961 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Books: Lifeblood of the University, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Center for International Studies, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - The Cornell Faculty: Key to Excellence, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - The Avalon Foundation, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Faculty Research: A Tool for Better Teaching, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 72)